A Guide to the Virginia Military District Land Surveys, 1787-1823
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Military District Land Surveys, 1787-1823
The Library of Virginia
50288
.225 cubic feet (1 box)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Historical Information
The Virginia Military District was an approximately 4.2 million acre area of land in what is now the state of Ohio that was reserved by Virginia to use for bounty land awards for veterans of the Revolutionary War. The land was located in southern Ohio, bordered by the Ohio River on the south, the Little Miami River on the west, and the Scioto River on the east and the north. The District included all of the following Ohio counties: Adams, Brown, Clinton, Clermont, Highland, Fayette, Madison and Union, and portions of these counties: Scioto, Pike, Ross, Pickaway, Franklin, Delaware, Marion, Hardin, Logan, Clark, Greene, Champaign. Warren, Hamilton and Auglaize. Surveys were done using the metes and bounds method used in Virginia.
Scope and Content
Surveys, 1787-1823, of land awarded by Virginia to Revolutionary War veterans, their heirs, or assignees, located in the present state of Ohio. There are 67 surveys in this collection. They include the name of the warrantee, description of the land boundaries, survey map, signature of the surveyor, and, in some cases, date of the survey.
Contents List
- Allen, Nathaniel, 100 acres, 20 April 1797. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Beasley, John, 400 acres, 16 March 1797. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bohannon, Ambrose, 1000 acres, 14 July 1796. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Carrington, Mayo, 1000 acres, November 1787. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Crawford, John, 300 acres, 5 April 1797. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Crawford, John, 175 acres, 15 January 1798. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Davis, David, 1000 acres, 2 June 1796. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Denny, Aaron, 1000 acres, 22 June 1792. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Denny, Aaron, 1000 acres, 27 June 1792. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Duncan, David, 200 acres, 20 June 1795. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ellison, Andrew, 207 acres, 27 May 1796. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ellison, Andrew, 50 acres, 11 June 1812. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ellison, John Jr., 40 acres, 10 June 1823. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Flinn, Osburn, 400 acres, 22 April 1796. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gatewood, A., 470 acres, 22 April 1795. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gatewood, A., 250 acres, 19 June 1795. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gatewood, A., 380 acres, 20 June 1795. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Goodin, Benjamin, 330 acres, 20 March 1801. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Goodin, Benjamin, 250 acres, 17 October 1801. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Goodin, Benjamin, 280 acres, 21 October 1801. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Green, Robert, 666 acres, 2 February 1787. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Griffin, John T., 1666 2/3 acres, 4 January 1792. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Harrison, Charles, 1200 acres, 16 October 1792. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Harrison, Charles, 1200 acres, 17 October 1792. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hendricks, Byrd, 1000 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Heth, William, 900 acres, 12 October 1798. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hill, Thomas, 5333 1/3 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Holladay, William, 300 acres, 11 April 1810. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hopkins, Sam, 1400 acres, 14 October 1792. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hopkins, Samuel, 1400 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- James, Thomas, 285 2/3 acres, 16 December 1818. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Jameson, John, 1000 acres, 27 March 1791. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ludeman, J. William, 1494 acres, 27 May and 1 August 1794. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ludeman, J. William, 1494 acres, 27 May1794. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lytle, William, 500 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Maple, George, 100 acres, 29 February 1808. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Marshall, Richard, 200 acres, 21 February 1796. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Massie, Nathaniel, 720 acres, 20 February 1795. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Massie, Nathaniel, 231 acres, 10 September 1796. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Massie, Nathaniel, 553 acres, 10 October 1796. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Massie, Nathaniel, 360 acres, 27 April 1797. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Massie, Nathaniel, 300 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Massie, Nathaniel (Heirs), 1000 acres, 25 June 1815. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Matthews, George, 2000 acres, 6 April 1792. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- McClanahan, Thomas, 100 acres, 19 August 1809. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- McDorman, David, 200 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- McDowell, John, 1000 acres, 18 November 1787. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minnis, Colohill, 1000 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Morgan, Simon, 477 acres, 24 December 1796. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Morrison, Robert, 100 acres, 18 November 1798. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Nourse, Robert, 200 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Payne, William, 1300 acres, 3 April and 28 June 1792. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Peyton, Francis, 2000 acres, 20 February 1794. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Peyton, Francis, 1380 acres, 29 June 1795. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Peyton, Timothy, 1000 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pollard, Robert, 100 acres, 25 July 1797. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Rodgers, George, 200 acres, 6 April 1803. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Rogers, Bernard, 200 acres, 4 June 1811. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Scott, Charles, 2000 acres, 10 April and 18 July 1796. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Shepherd, A., 1200 acres, 14 March 1797. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Shepherd, A., 1065 acres, 15 March 1797. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Shepherd, A., 300 acres, 16 March 1797. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Smith, Francis, 1000 acres, 6 March 1794. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Steel, John, 778 acres, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Taylor, Francis, 1000 acres, 28 March 1792. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Thomas, Michael, 100 acres, 16 October 1801. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- White, Robert, 100 acres, 15 May 1806. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Wood, William, 200 acres, 15 August 1797. (Box 1, Folder 4)